Guide to the William Rainey Harper Papers 1872-1938
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Personal
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, N-O (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, P (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, R (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, S (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, T-V (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Harper, W-Z, and unidentified (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Letters of sympathy to Samuel Harper (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, A-B (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, C-D (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, E-H (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, I-L (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, M (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, N-P (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, R-S] (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others, T-V (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Letter of sympathy to University official and others,, W-Z (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Poems and miscellaneous tributes to Harper (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Letters about Harper (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Memorial magazines (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Memorial magazines (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Clippings about Harper (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence concerning plaque for Harper's Desk (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Handbill, 1872, New Concord, Ohio, advertising The New Concord Silver Cornet Band, with W.R. Harper as leader (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "William Rainey Harper,” Bound Typescript (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous biographical materials (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Memorial service programs, eulogies, and obituaries (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Writings
  - Writings, "The Study of the Bible by College Students," Report of the Fifth Annual Conference of the Young Men's Christian Association of New England Colleges, 1887 "The University and Democracy," University Chronicle 2/2, 1899 "The Educational Progress of the Year 1901-2," Proceedings of the National Education Association, 1902 "The College President," Educational Record, 1938 (prepared as an address in 1904) "The College President," University of Chicago Magazine, November 1938 (reprinted) (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies of Works by William Rainey Harper and Reviews of Works by William Rainey Harper (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series V: Books from the Library of William Rainey Harper
  - Books, Köigliche Museen zu Berlin, F?hrer durch das Alte und das Neue Museum, 1891 L. Sauveur, Introduction to the Teaching of Living Languages without Grammar or Dictionary, 1874 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Prophetae Posteriores, Hebrew text of the Later Prophets with annotations by Harper throughout (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Notebooks and Scrapbooks
  - Subseries 1: W.R. Harper "Red Books"
    - [1887-1888] (Volume I)
    - August 24 [1892] (Volume II)
    - [1893] (Volume III)
    - May 30, 1893 (Volume IV)
    - December, 1893 (Volume V)
    - May, 1894 (Volume VI)
    - December 29, 1894 (Volume VII)
    - 1896 (Volume VIII)
    - February 17, 1897 (Volume X)
    - October 1, 1897 (Volume XI)
    - April 1898 (Volume XII)
    - October 1, 1898 (Volume XIII)
    - July 5, 1899 (Volume XIV)
    - December 12, 1899 (Volume XV)
    - January 1, 1900 (Volume XVI)
    - October 1, 1890 (Volume XVII)
    - July 1, 1901 (Volume XVIII)
    - April 1, [1902] (Volume XIX)
    - [1903-1904] (Volume XX)
    - April 15, 1904 (Volume XXI)
    - no date (Volume XXII)
  - Subseries 2: W.R. Harper Miscellaneous Notebooks
    - "Hebrew Correspondence, Club conducted by W.R. Harper, Baptist Union Theol. Sem., Morgan Park, Chicago, Ill., [treasurer's book] (Notebook I)
    - "The American Institute of Sacred Literature" [1893-1895] (Notebook II)
    - "Editorial Book for 1895 - 1896" (Notebook III)
    - "Editorial Memoranda May 1st 1898" (Notebook IV)
    - [Petitions?] September 8, 1896 to May 11 [1897] (Notebook V)
    - [Pocket memorandum book] no date (Notebook VI)
    - [Pocket memorandum book] no date (Notebook VII)
    - [Notes on study of Arabic?] (Notebook VIII)
  - Subseries 3: W.R. Harper Secretary's Notebooks
    - "The President's Annual Report -- 1898" (Notebook I)
    - 1898-1899 (Notebook II)
    - 1899 (Notebook III)
    - 1900 (Notebook IV)
    - 1900-01 (Notebook V)
    - 1901-02 (Notebook VI)
    - 1902-03 (Notebook VII)
    - 1903 (Notebook VIII)
    - 1904 (Notebook IX)
    - "General Reference Book" (Notebook X)
  - Subseries 4: Harper - Shepardson Business Correspondence
    - 1900-1903 (Volume I)
    - 1902-1904 (Volume II)